我之前打过电话 关于一位失踪的美国公民 他现在在中东
I called earlier about a missing U.S. Citizen in the Middle East.
莎拉 你还好吗
How are you, Sara?
我需要见国务院的人 而不是你
I wanted the State Department, not you.
有没有可能波塞冬会准许我们杀了她
Any chance Poseidon will just let us kill her?
我得到了些情报
I've learned some things
很显然关乎你我正在共同寻找的人
about who it is we're apparently both looking for.
你觉得迈克尔在也门
You think Michael's in Yemen?
-我们来救你出去  -我不认识你
- We're gonna get you out of here. - I don't know who you are.
你弟弟通过这家店来逃跑
Your brother was using this shop for his escape.
我们过来拿护照
We're here for passports.
我们有一天时间离开这个鬼地方
Figure we got a day to get out of this hole.
我们都会出去的 所有人
We're still getting out. All of us.
波塞冬把我们塞进来是为了救拉马尔出去
Poseidon put us in here to get Ramal out,
但之后他抛弃了我们
but then he abandoned us.
拉马尔是波塞冬的人 不是我们的
Ramal's Poseidon's guy, not ours.
我们的朋友告诉了我越狱计划
Our friend told me about the escape.
他会背叛你
He will betray you.
等灯都灭了
When those lights go black,
我们会像幽灵般从这里逃之夭夭
we're gonna disappear from this place like ghosts.
我打不开
I can't get it open.
帮帮我上去
Help me out.
你先把我兄弟拉上来
You pull my brother up first.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
身体还好
Body is fine.
脑袋里嘛
My head is
还在想怎么拿到那些
trying to figure out how to get those passports
我们昨晚没拿到的护照
we couldn't get last night.
你和孩子们的护照
For you, those kids.
那些事
Well, that's something you shouldn't
不是你现在要担心的
be worrying about right now.
你该休息好 我们之后还需要你
You should rest up. We're gonna need you.
死了就能好好休息了
I can rest when I'm dead.
那也是我担心的
Well, that's what I'm worried about.
我不知道你还会担心
Didn't know you worried.
我只担心对的事
About the right things.
你弟弟
Your brother.
他逃出来了吗
He make it out?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
希巴 我可以和林肯单独聊一下吗
Sheba, do you mind if I borrow Linc for a second?
-当然  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
好好休息
Please get some rest.
听着 我们得考虑
Listen. We got to start talking
离开这个国家了
about leaving the country.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我跟清真寺的朋友谈过
I spoke to my friends at the mosque.
伊斯兰国将在一小时内占领周边地区
ISIL is taking neighborhoods by the hour.
如果他们切断了去机场的路线...
If they cut off the route to the airport...
我不会丢下迈克尔的
I'm not leaving Michael.
如果他们封锁了机场 那就谁都能逃不出去了
If they cut off the airport, no one is getting out.
你 我 希巴都逃不出去
Not you, me, Sheba.
这么说我也很难过...
As much as it kills me to say...
但我们不能为了一个人...
we can't risk all of it for...
拿这一切冒险
just one man.
你说的对
You're right.
你走吧
You can leave.
但我不能走
But I can't.
你尽快把那家人都带去机场
Get that family to the airport as fast as you can.
我再想想办法
I'll work something out.
布鲁斯先生
Mr. Burrows?
谢谢你救了我女儿
I wanted to thank you for saving my daughter.
我想回报你
And offer you something in appreciation.
我可能有办法救你弟弟
I might have a solution for how to get your brother
逃出那所监狱
out of that prison.
趁这座城市还没有被夷为平地
Before the city goes to hell.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
这次是目前最近的炮击
That was the closest one yet!
离我们不到100米
100 yards!
你还说不会更糟
Just when you think it couldn't get worse
我们被困在这个没有出路的鬼地方了
locked up in a Porta Potti,
他们都开始往这里扔2000磅的炸弹了
they start dropping 2,000-pound bombs on the Porta Potti.
维普 冷静点
Whip. Keep it together, please.
越狱大师有点紧张了啊
The escape artist is nervous.
你也应该紧张才对
You should be, too.
那些大炮不断攻击 炮弹可不会分辨敌我
Those artillery strikes, they don't discriminate.
我和你不一样 我有信仰
The difference is I have faith.
真主会拯救我的
Allah will deliver me.
谁来拯救你呢
What do you have?
贾
Ja!
贾 你在吗
Ja, are you there?
我在这儿
I'm here.
维普说的对
Whip's right.
袭击越来越近了
The strikes are getting closer.
我真可怜你
I pity you.
不管如何我都会胜利
I triumph either way.
要么上天堂 要么真主会拯救我
Either I will be in paradise or Allah will save me.
你
You,
你会死
you're just going to die.
伊斯兰国攻破了检查站
ISIL has broken through the checkpoints.
他们要进城了
They're coming into the city.
这些制服就像是
These uniforms are like targets
-我们背上的活靶子  -伊斯兰国还没到呢
- on our backs. - ISIL isn't here yet.
政府说会把他们打回去的
The government says it will push them back.
你疯了吧 这是不可能的
You out of your head? This is happening.
萨那城已经沦陷了
Sana'a is falling.
他们要逃跑了
They're going to retreat.
我之前见过那种表情
I've seen that look before in the army.
他们会为了保全自己不择手段
Men who will do anything to save themselves.
那我们怎么办
And how do we save ourselves?
要是伊斯兰国攻破这座监狱 第一个杀的就是我们
ISIL takes this prison, we'll be the first they slaughter.
他们攻下这座监狱
When they take this prison, it will be
是为了解救他们的领袖拉马尔
to liberate their leader, Ramal,
但如果他们进来的时候
but if when they get here,
我们拿刀
we have him with a knife
抵住拉马尔的喉咙
to his throat,
然后我们就有话语权了
then we call the shots.
说不定能活下来
And we might just live.
维普 我有本圣母经[双关语 也有绝妙的点子的意思]
Whip, I got a Hail Mary.
-你要祈祷还是有点子了  -点子
- That a prayer or a plan? - Plan.
我上次进这里的时候留下了些东西
I left something the last time I was in here.
我猜猜 你碰上了意外
Let me guess, you got a contingency.
他们关了我4年
They lock me away in a box for four years.
我是不会坐以待毙的
I'm not just gonna sit there.
机会渺茫 但有可能让我们逃出去
It's a long shot, but it might get us out.
异教徒还想着逃跑
The infidel still tries to escape.
绝望的小老鼠
The desperate rat.
我们这些绝望的小老鼠一出去
The desperate rat's gonna light you up
就会烧死你
once we get out of here,
-你这个长着虫眼的变态  -维普
- you bugged-eyed freak. - Whip.
维普 一个S 那儿有没有一个S
Whip! An "S." Is there an "S"
刻在角落的墙上
carved in your wall chest high
大概胸部高的地方
in the corner?
拜托 拜托
Come on, come on.
没有
That's not it.
我什么都没看到
I'm not seeing anything.
没看到
I'm not seeing it.
贾 那肯定在你那儿了
Ja, it's got to be you.
快 告诉我你墙上刻着一个S
Come on. Tell me you got an "S" Carved in your wall.
那是我们最后的机会了
It's our last chance.
没有
No.
没在这儿 没有
It's not here, no.
那是因为在我这儿
That's because I have it in my cell.
我的军队
My armies of the caliphate
越来越近了
are coming closer.
他们一到这个地方
The moment they reach this place,
你们这些人 就会像狗一样被干掉
all of you will be put down like the dogs that you are.
好了 萨拉
All right, Sara.
我们的朋友波塞冬露面了
Our friend, Poseidon, has surfaced.
天呐
Good God.
伊斯兰国又攻击了
Another ISIL attack.
他们在把这个城市撕成碎片
They're ripping the city apart.
他们就是禽兽
They're animals.
我一辈子都是个官僚主义者
I've been a bureaucrat my whole life.
但我很讨厌官僚主义
Hated it.
贪污 黑幕
Corruption, backslapping.
但今天 官僚主义可能也有点好处
But today, maybe some good will come of it.
我跟这个叫易卜拉欣的男生
I went to grammar school with this boy
一起读的初中
named Ibrahim.
这些年后 他成了联邦法官
All the years later, he's a federal judge.
你是说这个法官能帮我们吗
You, uh, saying this judge can help us?
几小时前我给他打了电话
I called him a few hours ago and told him
和他说了你弟弟的案子
about your brother's case.
你重新装潢了
Redecorating, I see.
为了即将到来的变动做好准备
Just readying for the coming change of seasons.
奢侈品令伊斯兰教徒不悦
Luxury is something the Wahabbists frown upon,
所以要把它们藏起来
so luxury will stay behind closed doors.
你该逃离这个国家
You should flee the country.
我不会死的 你知道的
I'm a survivor, you know that.
也许布鲁斯先生
I thought Mr. Burrows could perhaps
能帮得上他弟弟的忙
help with his brother's cause.
噢 对了
Ah, yes.
最高司法委员会的无条件赦免
A full pardon from the Supreme Judicial Council.
但交易结束后才能给你
But you will have to uphold your end of the bargain,
贾米勒
Jamil.
德国车 公里数七万七
German engineering. 77,000 miles.
油耗五升 七速变速箱 V10发动机
Five liter, seven speed, V10.
是个受欢迎的奢侈品
It will be a welcome bit of luxury.
当然 不为人知
Behind closed doors, of course.
祝你们好运
Best of luck to both of you.
非常感谢你帮忙
I really appreciate this.
谢谢
Thank you.
事已至此
It's already done.
反正也留不了
It would've been left behind anyhow.
希望我们的家人
May both of our families
今夜都能从萨那安全逃出
get safely out of Sana'a tonight.
我们不能在这里坐以待毙
We can't just sit here and die.
你有个跟这一样的窗户 对吧
You-you got a window like this one, right?
我们也许可以撬开它
Maybe we can pry it.
这窗户太小而且经过加固
It's too small, reinforced.
基础结构里内置了钢筋
Built into the rebar infrastructure.
你在外面有接应的吧
You got people on the outside, right?
他们会想办法救我们出去的
And they're gonna try and get us out.
他们本该昨晚在商店与我们汇合
They were supposed to meet us at the shop
但我们没出现
last night and we didn't show.
我们不能放弃
We can't just quit
-被波塞冬击败  -拉马尔
- and let Poseidon beat us. - Ramal?
如果我们携手 还有一个办法可以逃出去
There's a way out if we work together,
但必须先从你的牢房开始
but escape has to start from your cell.
我再也感兴趣了
I'm no longer interested.
你唯一能做的就是摇尾乞怜
The only thing left for you to do is to beg.
等我的人来了后 求我饶你一命
Beg that I might let you live once my armies came,
前提是作为奴隶
if only as a slave.
这七年我一直是奴隶
I've been a slave for the last seven years.
我不会再当了
I won't do it anymore!
你死了以后我会想你的
I will miss you when you're dead,
不过也就想个一分钟
but only for a minute.
然后 你就会被
Then you will be forgotten
时间和世界遗忘
by both time and the world.
她也是我的女儿 辛迪
Well, she's my kid, too, Cindy.
周末是我的...
I have the weekends and...
不行 周末是我的
Well, no, I have the weekends
我不要周三下午
and I don't want a Wednesday afternoon.
我为什么要那样
Why would I want that?
没人会想
Yeah, nobody does.
这样可以 辛迪
No, that's okay, Cindy.
没问题
Yeah, that's fine.
其它天呢
What other days?
你还要想要哪些天
What other days do you want?
你知道吗
Actually, you know what?
我现在不想谈这个
I don't want to discuss this now.
不 我们之后再谈
No, we'll talk about it later.
挂了
Bye.
我被释放以后
Of all the things
这个世界里最困扰我的
that mystify me in this world
其中一件事情
since I've been released,
就是甘蓝的风靡一时
is that kale is the rage.
甘蓝
Kale.
西奥多·巴格威尔
Theodore Bagwell.
同样让我迷惑的
Thing that mystifies me equally
是七年前
is seven years ago,
你赦免了迈克尔
you exonerated Michael,
林肯 所有人
Lincoln, all of them,
除了我
except me.
-逗我呢  -爽
- Really? - Yes!
你就为这事来找我吗
That's why you're here?
因为我没赦免你吗
Because I didn't exonerate you?
一个杀人犯
A murderer,
多次性侵犯
a sexual predator a dozen times over.
这都是"过去"的事了
"Was" Is the key word.
我现在是光明正大的人
I'm a man moving toward the light now,
正义还在召唤我
and the light's beckoning me.
我只是不知道是谁在幕后操纵
I just don't know who's pulling the strings.
不过萨拉说是你
But Sara says it's you.
噢 萨拉派你来找我的吗
Oh, Sara put you onto me?
好吧
Okay.
我不知道谁更蠢
I don't know who the bigger idiot is,
你还是她
you or her.
我在帮她忙
I was helping her.
你黑了她手机还派人
You were hacking her phone and sending those people
跟踪她...别...
after her... Don't...
撒谎
lie.
现在...
Now...
不如告诉我你的其中一个见不得人的任务
how about you pour me one of them nasty little kale jobbies,
和斯科菲尔德与我有什么关系
and tell me what's all this got to do with Scofield and myself,
你的朋友是谁
who your friends are,
你是谁...我想看看
who you are... I want to see
幕后操纵我的究竟是谁
the true face of who's pulling my strings
彻底搞清楚
once and for all.
有两位来访者在大厅等您
You have two visitors in the lobby.
告诉他们我马上就来
Tell them I'll be right down.
嗨
Hey.
交给我 格蕾丝
I got this, Grace.
他们在城里
They're in the city.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
你觉得呢
What do you think I'm doing?
狗东西 不许逃
Don't run, you dog!
不许逃
Don't run!
他们要逃了 准备好
It is happening. Be ready.
这个赦免令最好能把他救出来
This pardon better get him out of here.
时间不够了...我们必须去见监狱长
We don't have much time... we have to get to the warden.
怎么回事
What's going on?
他们准备弃狱 所以易卜拉欣
They're abandoning the prison. That's why Ibrahim
给我们赦免令
gave us that pardon.
他知道根本没用
He knew it was worthless.
你和C-Note带其他人去机场
You and C-Note get the others to the airport
越快越好... 也许还有航班
as fast as you can... There's maybe one flight out.
留两座位
Save two seats.
好吗
All right?
你准备怎么做
What are you going to do?
我要去救我弟弟
I'm gonna get my brother.
穆斯塔法
Mustapha!
后退
Back up!
后退 近我者死
Back up. Anyone comes at me, dies.
-懂吗  -你能打死我们所有人吗
- Understand? - You think you can shoot all of us?
谁还想碰运气
Anyone else want to play the lottery?
一群垃圾
Huh? You're filth.
就让伊斯兰国收拾你们吧
I'll let ISIL sort you out.
穆斯塔法
Mustapha!
穆斯塔法 等等我
Mustapha! Mustapha, wait!
别把我关在这
Don't lock me in here!
你个懦夫
You coward.
穆斯塔法 求求你
Mustapha, please.
懦夫
Coward!
我要进去 我要进去
I need to get in! I need to get out!
-给我钥匙  -我没钥匙
- Well, give me the key. - I don't have the key.
你和有钥匙的人擦肩而过
You passed the guy who does.
退后 我不想杀你们
Stay back! I don't want to shoot you!
警卫都跑了
The guards are gone!
他们弃狱而逃
They're abandoning their posts!
我们要自由了
We're gonna be free!
不 我们没有
No. We're not free.
情况变得更糟了
Things just got a lot worse.
把门撞开
Push the gate open!
停 停
Stop! Stop!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
-我们必须逃出去  -如果伊斯兰国占领了城市
- We have to get through the gate! - If ISIL controls the city,
像他们说的那样 外面也一样水深火热
like they say, it will be a prison out there as well.
如果我们被关在这里
We will be persecuted,
我们会被处死 情况只会变得更糟
as we have been in here, only worse!
至少还有活的机会
At least there's a chance!
你们想要机会是吗
You want a chance?
我们的机会就在那里
Our chance lies in there,
单人牢房里
in solitary.
我们的筹码
Our bargaining chip.
我们拿下阿布·拉马尔
We get Abu Ramal!
我们可以谈判
We negotiate passage
离开这个国家
out of the country.
不 这太疯狂了
No, it's madness.
拜托 如果我们合作 可以推开这道门
Come on. If we work together, we can push open the gate.
是你吗 小公主
Is that you, Princess?
是你 我们都记得这家伙
It is you. We remember this one!
-对吗 我们都记得他  -拜托...
- Right? We remember him! - Please...
坎尼尔·奥提斯的朋友
Friend to Kaniel Outis,
那个不愿意对我弟弟伸出援手的男人
the man who would not lend my brother a hand!
依我看 他才是
The man who killed my brother,
杀掉我弟弟的人 对吧
as far as I'm concerned, right?
-我们进去拿下阿布·拉马尔  -不 拜托
- We are going to go in there and get Abu Ramal! - No! Please!
-不 拜托  -等我们进去里面后
- No! Please! - And when we are there,
我会亲手割开坎尼尔·奥提斯的喉咙
I am personally going to slice Kaniel Outis' throat.
而你 就是帮我实现这件事的人
And you are going to be the one who's going to help me do it.
-不  -你押他过去
- No! - You sent him!
带上他
Take him!
你们所有人
All of you!
你们是要留在这里
Will you stay here?
等着被伊斯兰国的人屠杀
And let ISIL slaughter you?
还是跟我一起
Or will you stand with me?
抵抗他们
And fight!
听起来可不乐观
Doesn't sound very promising!
拉马尔
Ramal,
你要重新考虑一下帮助我们吗
you want to rethink helping us?
越狱必须从
Escape has to start
你的牢房开始
from your cell!
你们这些异教徒都可以下地狱
All you infidels can go to Hell!
我们现在就在地狱 拉马尔
We are in Hell, Ramal.
问题是 你想离开吗
Question is do you want out?
撞开这扇门
Smash through the door!
告诉我该怎么做
Tell me what to do.
快点 快点...
Come on, come on...
我没有黑过任何人的手机
I'm not hacking anybody's phones.
这件事你完全搞错了
You're so off base on this,
你根本不明白
you have no idea.
我不明白吗
Am I?
是 是的
Y-Yes.
这菜汁太难喝了
That is terrible,
顺带问一下 那是什么
by the way. What is that,
悔悟行为吗
an act of contrition?
像苦行僧的粗毛衬衣
Like a hair shirt?
喝蔬菜汁折磨自己来弥补你的的罪过吗
Torture yourself with kale to make up for your sins?
我没有任何罪过 伙计
I don't have any sins anymore, man.
-你才有罪  -欺骗罪怎么样
- That's you. - How about the sin of deceit?
嗯哼
Hmm?
一个叫做凯勒曼的在白天喝蔬菜汁的男人
A kale-drinking man named Kellerman by the light of day,
一个叫做波塞冬的在晚上蓄意杀人的CIA禽兽
a murderous CIA rogue named Poseidon at night.
波塞冬
Poseidon?
他的眼睛发光了
His eyes light up.
她是对的
She was right.
噢 你认为我是波塞冬吗
Oh, you think I'm Poseidon?
好吧
Okay.
你和波塞冬搞混了吗
Are you mixed up with Poseidon?
噢 见鬼
Oh, hell,
我们非得用些老办法吗
we got to go old school with this?
那是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
-T-Bag式断手指
- T-Bag snapping fingers.
这非常... 你刚好给了我一些可以合作的信息
That's very... you just gave me something to work with.
-波塞冬吗  -波塞冬
- Poseidon? - Poseidon.
我会告诉你波塞冬的事情
I'll tell you about Poseidon.
我是说 他就是你听说过的这个体系中的神话之一
I mean, he's one of those myths you hear about in the system.
他是一个触不可及的特工
He's an operative so untouchable,
藏得如此之深 如果没有核潜艇 你根本找不到他
so deep, you couldn't find him with a nuclear sub.
这就是他的绰号的来源
Hence the nickname.
那么这是怎么牵涉到我的
And how does this involve me?
他想从迈克尔那里得到什么
What's he want with Michael?
拉马尔 听清楚了
Ramal, listen closely.
刻有S的那块砖是松的
The brick with the "S," It's loose.
你要移开它
You got to remove it.
里面有一把勺子和一根绳
It's a spoon, string.
-怎么做  -那绳子来自
- How? - A string a day from
我穿了四年的狱服
my uniforms for four years.
勺子是千百次机会才被狱警忽视一次得到的
A spoon a guard overlooked one time in a thousand.
你的头上有一根水管
There's a water pipe above you.
钩住它 把它拉下来
Hook it, pull it down.
快做
Do it!
喂 我直说了 这是救他出去吗
Hey. Let me get this straight. This is getting him out?
这是救我们所有人出去
It's getting us all out.
这需要两个牢房的合作 我的和他的
This is a two-cell job, mine and his.
那就是我在那个牢房时不能拉下水管的原因
That's why I couldn't pull it off when I was in that cell,
因为我对面牢房的那个人
because the guy across from me,
当时在这个牢房里的人 不愿意合作
the guy in this cell, wouldn't cooperate.
我们必须合作
We have to work together.
快点
Come on!
-不  -十字架[绰号]
- No. - Cross!
我不会跟你合作的
I'm not working with you.
不 不
No. No.
来这里 过来 小甜心
Come here! Come on, sweetheart.
亮下你漂亮的脸 来 上到这来
Show them your pretty face! Come on, get up here!
看着 停下你们正在做的事
Look! Stop what you're doing
告诉坎尼尔·奥提斯我会杀了这个娘炮
and tell Kaniel Outis I will kill the girl!
把他带走
Take him!
快点 我们俩还没完
Come on! I'm not through with you yet!
他们在外面揍希德 他们会杀了他
They're beating the crap out of Sid. They'll kill him
-除非我们投降  -如果我们投降
- unless we surrender. - If we surrender,
他们会杀了我们 他们只想需要拉马尔
they'll kill us. They only want Ramal.
我们救希德最好的机会是离开这里
Our best chance of saving Sid is getting out of here.
让他们忽略掉他 转而来追我们
Make them forget about him, start chasing us.
好吧 好吧
Okay, good.
现在捡起它 把绳子系上去
Now pick it up. String the cord
穿过它
and pull it through.
加油 加油
Come on, come on!
耶
Yeah!
我会杀了这个娘炮 我发誓
I will kill the girl, I swear it!
别
No!
我再说一遍
I will say it again,
在我的监管下
there will not be any killing in this prison!
这个监狱里不允许有任何杀戮
Not on my watch!
这简直是疯了
This is completely insane.
外面正在上演该死的墨西哥肥皂剧
It's a freakin' Mexican soap opera out here!
拉马尔 别停下 别胡思乱想
Ramal, don't stop. Don't start thinking.
别把希望寄托在一个狱警上
Don't pin your hopes on one guard.
走开
Walk away!
躲到牢房里去
Hide in the cell block!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
监狱已经完了 老兄
The prison is done, brother.
看在上帝的份上
For the love of God!
看在上帝的份上 一个男人正在寻求正义
For the love of God, a man seeks justice.
这就是他每时每刻都在做的事情
In everything he does, at all times!
现在 所有人 回到你们的牢房里
Now, everybody, back in the block!
这里已经不存在犯人和狱警了
There are no prisoners and guards anymore!
你也意识到了 对吗
You realize that, right?
一旦伊斯兰国的人到了这里
If ISIL gets in here,
我们都是他们的敌人
we are all the enemy.
罪人
Sinners,
异教徒...
deviants...
和那些关住他们首领的人
and those that locked up their leader.
你将是他们抓获的唯一的狱警
You will be the only guard that they catch.
高尚的那个
The noble one.
他们会砍掉你的头 但是...
They will behead you for it. But...
如果我们合作
if we work together,
我们抓住拉马尔
we get Ramal,
我们就有了筹码
we have a bargaining chip.
我会安排好一切
I will see to it
你能跟我们一起离开这里
that you will get out with the rest of us.
只要你给我单人牢房的钥匙
Just give me the keys to solitary.
我没有那些钥匙
I don't have the keys.
我知道你有
I know you do.
加入我们
Join us
你就能活下来
and you will live.
我向你保证
I give you my word.
我没有钥匙
I don't have them.
杀了他
Kill him!
但是你有更好的东西 不是吗
But you have something much better, huh?
让开 让开
Move. Move!
我的天
Oh, my God.
天啦 他们杀了警卫
Oh, my God. They killed the guard!
警卫死了 他们要来找我们了
The guard is gone, they're comging for us.
一定要成功 拉马尔
Got to make this count, Ramal.
把鱼竿从小槽伸出来
String that fishing pole through that slot.
就这样
That's right.
现在 把轮轴拿掉
Now, you can remove the pinions
在我的门上...铰链
on my door... the hinges.
有两个
There are two of them.
不可能
No way.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
干什么呢
我要开我的门
I'm doing mine.
我们没时间浪费了 拉马尔
We don't have time for this, Ramal!
我跟你说 这需要两间牢房合作
I'm telling you, it's a two-cell job,
那才是关键 这一边的牢房
that's the point. That side of the wing
都是新装的 那些轮轴
is new construction. The pinions
都被铰链遮住了... 你弄不掉的
are covered in the hinges... You can't pull them.
我这边的是老式的 没有铰链 而且很松
This side is original. They're open, loose.
你想让我放了你
You want me to free you?
然后我会去拿那边的钥匙再放了你
Yes, and I, in turn, free you with those keys, down there.
我为什么要信你 不信外面那个疯子
Why would I trust you more than the madman out there?
因为你也听见了他的话到底有几分能信
Cause you just heard what his word is worth.
踹门
Kick it.
你选吧 到底谁更值得相信
This is it. It's all about whose word you trust.
我发誓... 你放了我
I promise you... you release me,
我就放了你
I release you.
再来点 再来点
Little more, little more.
感谢老天 加油
Thank God. Come on.
好了 下面的
Okay, the bottom.
太好了
Yes!
加油
Come on,
-快点 快点  -加油
- come on. Come on. - Come on.
好了
Yes!
快好了
Almost there!
太好了
Yes.
加油
Come on.
快点 加油啊
Got to hurry up, come on.
好 好 太棒了
Yes. Yes, come on!
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
放了我
Open my door.
我要赶快从这鬼地方走人
I'm getting the hell out of here.
给我开门
Open my door.
-留他在这儿 兄弟 你疯了吗  -快放了我
- Leave him, man, you crazy? - Open my door.
我们一旦出去了
Once we're outside these walls, we need
需要能顺利出国的安全路线
safe passage out of the country.
都现在了 你还想谈条件
Even now, you negotiate.
不合作 咱们都得死
We work together or we both die.
我保证
You have my word.
开门
Open the door.
我们得快走
We got to go now.
不 不
No, no!
嘀嗒糖先生
Mr. Tic Tac.
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
你要跟伊斯兰国的人战斗吗
You gonna fight ISIL men?
快离开这 小家伙 躲起来
Get out of here, kid, hide!
-这儿不是你们待的地方  -你要跟伊斯兰国的人战斗吗
- This is no place for you. - You gonna fight ISIL men?
对
Yes.
你仔细听好了 好吗
Listen very closely, all right?
美国人 美国人
American! American!
有美国人
American!
-你现在要去救泡泡糖先生吗  -是啊
- You go to Bubble Gum Man now? - Yeah.
谢谢你帮忙 给 拿着
Thanks for your help. Here, take that.
去个安全的地方 好吗
Get somewhere safe, okay?
嘀嗒糖先生去救泡泡糖先生了
Mr. Tic Tac goes to Bubble Gum Man!
拉马尔... 我不想杀你
Ramal... don't want to kill you.
只杀你的朋友 懂了吗
Just your friends. You understand?
来这儿干嘛 有什么用啊
What are we doing in here? This is not helping us.
为了遵守咱们的约定
You're gonna make a phone call
你得打个电话出去
so you can hold up your end of the deal.
纳什温广场有一间汽车维修厂
There's an auto body shop off Nashwan plaza.
我需要加满油的车
I want vehicles there, full tanks of gas
这样我们所有人才能去边境
so we can get to the border, all of us.
我不要跟你去边境
I'm not going with you to the border.
你没得选
You don't have a choice.
到了边境 我们就能分开了
We're gonna ride to the border, then say sayonara.
你是我们的通行证啊
You're our insurance.
拉马尔 我不想杀你
Ramal, I don't want to kill you.
懂吗
You understand?
还是说你想当外面那些人的保票  拿着
Or would you rather be their insurance? Take it.
我想知道他说了什么 他有可能会耍咱们
I want to know what he's saying. He could be screwing us.
他肯定是在耍我们
He's screwing with us, all right.
我们得在他动手前先弄他
We just need to screw with him first.
贾呢
Where's Ja?
我不知道
I don't know.
-羟考酮...  -咱们得走了
- Oxycodone... - Hey, we got to peel.
镇痛药...
Percocet...
快点 你个王八蛋日本药虫
Come on, you Japanese junkie son of a bitch.
我是韩国人 你个加拿大猴子
I'm Korean, you Canadian monkey.
加拿大人 真搞笑 贾
Canadian? Oh, that's really funny, Ja.
咱们要不是快被杀了 我一定会笑岔气的
You'd split my sides if we weren't about to be slaughtered.
嘿 记住伍迪·艾伦说的话[著名美国导演]
Hey, remember what Woody Allen said.
说了什么
What did he say?
"我并不怕死
"I don't mind dying.
只不过是想在它来临时我恰巧不在"
I just don't want to be around when it happens."
嘿 好了
Hey, come on.
我们需要你 好吗
We need you, okay?
磨蹭什么呢
What's the holdup?
斯科菲尔德死定了
Scofield's a dead man.
敢和波塞冬有纠葛
He's tangling with Poseidon.
我知道你想干什么了
I see what you're doing here.
用第三人称说波塞冬
Talking Poseidon in third person,
假装你不是他
like you're not him.
国务院寻找波塞冬
State Department has been
找了好几年了
looking for Poseidon for years,
你个傻子 他是中情局的叛变特工
you idiot. He's a rogue CIA operative.
没人知道他是谁
Nobody knows who he is.
-开始瞎编了  -我知道
- Here we go. - I know it's a little
你一个普通罪犯肯定不会懂的
above your pay grade being a common criminal.
我们说的就只是一个人
I mean, we're talking about a single man.
对吗 一只猎鹰
Right? A hawk
他不喜欢白宫处理
who apparently doesn't like how the White House
对外政策的方式
goes about foreign policy,
所以决定自己动手
and decided to take matters into his own hands.
不用军队 不搞武装侵略
Not with armies, not with invasions,
只需要杀一个人
but by getting a single person killed,
或者让一个人当选
by getting a single person elected to office,
再或者把一个人从监狱放出来
by getting a single person released from prison.
监狱 迈克尔在的那个也门监狱吗
Prison, like the one in Yemen, where Michael's at.
想听我的猜测吗
You want my guess?
阿布·拉马尔才是波塞冬想放出来的那个人
It's Abu Ramal that Poseidon wants free.
我在监狱里的电视上看过他
Guy I seen on the prison telly.
等一下 我以为中情局是负责杀掉恐怖分子
Wait, I thought the CIA was supposed to kill terrorists,
-而不是放了他们啊  -波塞冬已经不是中情局的了
- not release them. - Poseidon is no longer CIA.
他不需要向谁复命
He doesn't report to anybody.
他只按自己的想法行事
He just pursues his own ideology.
好 举个例子 听好了
Okay, for instance, listen.
这样说 你觉得俄罗斯和伊朗
Let's say you think Russia and Iran
在中东地区势力太大了
are having too much influence in the Middle East,
你认为美国政府
and you don't think Washington
做的不好
is getting the job done.
所以你放了拉马尔
You free Ramal.
没错 他是个激进的伊斯兰疯子
Sure, he's an Islamic radical nut job,
但是他能帮你打击伊朗和俄罗斯 对吧
but he will fight Iran and Russia for you.
敌人的敌人是我的朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
波塞冬的精明之处在于
And what's so shrewd about Poseidon
他做的这些都不借助网络
is he does it all without a network,
所以他才这么难找
which is why he's so hard to find.
一个人就能做到这样吗
One man can pull strings like that?
一个控制着一大堆人的人
One man manipulating a handful of others.
阿布·拉马尔是个禽兽
Abu Ramal is a monster.
地狱早已经给他留好位置了
And there's a spot in Hell reserved for him,
但是最热门的位置还是要留给波塞冬
but the hottest spot is reserved for Poseidon,
因为他要让拉马尔重见天日
because he is letting Ramal loose on the world again.
那些人 他们手上有
Those men, they have the blood of thousands,
成千上万人的血
thousands on their hands.
跟他们比 咱们俩简直是天使
Compared to them, you and me are a couple of angels.
"天使"
"Angels"?
你发现了波塞冬是谁
You find out who Poseidon is,
也知道了斯科菲尔德是如何被困
and how Scofield is wrapped up in it,
也许你命中注定
maybe your fate...
要成为爱国者
is to be a patriot.
怎么回事
What...?
快走
Go. Go!
还有时间做任何事
There's a time for everything.
911 我需要援助 马上
911? I need help... now.
他们要往上走
They're going over the top.
我们走
Let's go.
快走 快走 快走
Go, go, go, go, go!
这边
This way!
锁住了
It's locked!
是条死路
It's a dead end.
不 不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no. No. No, no, no, no.
拉马尔
Ramal?
藏起来
Hide! Hide!
我不想杀你 只杀你朋友
I don't want to kill you! Just your friends.
-明白了吗  -锡德 你还活着吗
- You understand? - Sid, you're alive?
-走着瞧  -拉马尔
- We'll see about that. - Ramal?!
我们去把那龟孙子按倒
Let's hand the son of a bitch over.
没用的
Won't work.
他们会开枪把我们打趴下
They'll gun us down anyway.
那我们也不能等死啊
Can't just wait here and die.
游戏结束了
Your game is up.
出来
Come out!
无论是谁
Anyone
挡在我和阿布·拉马尔中间 都得死
who gets between me and Abu Ramal dies.
明白了吗
You understand?!
拉马尔在哪里
Where is Ramal?
马上告诉我
Tell me now!
有个男孩
There's a boy.
在纽约的伊萨卡岛 叫迈克·斯科菲尔德
Ithaca, New York. Mike Scofield.
万一我没活着出去
If I don't make it out of here alive,
跟他说他爸爸很爱他
tell him his father loves him very much.
"他爸爸"
"His father"?
如果我摁不住那把枪
If I don't smother that gun,
他们会把我们全杀了
they'll kill us all.
后退
Move back!
后退 快走
Move back! Go!
让我过去
Let me through!
迈克尔 迈克尔
Michael! Michael!
Michael? Michael!
波塞冬派你来的吗
Poseidon sent you?
你朋友呢
Where's your friend?
早就走远了
He's long gone.
后门那边
Back door.
从里面反锁了
Locked from the inside.
他在里面
He's in here.
找到他
Find him.
以前我也和你一样 为了谎言杀生
I was you once, killing for a lie.
那你现在呢
Now you're what?
为真相而死吗
Dying for the truth?
寻找真相是人的本性
It's human nature to find stuff out,
你也会这样的
so you will.
或者她会找到
Or she will.
然后谎言一方会来杀死知情者
And then the lie has to kill the truth.
下一个死的会是...
Which one of you is gonna die ne...?
没时间了
Time to get scarce.
嘿
Hey!
他对你说了什么
What did he say to you?
没什么
Nothing.
离汽车店还有好几个街区
Auto shop's a few blocks up.
你的人最好正在赶来
And your men better be coming.
他们会来的
They will be there.
贾在哪里
Where is Ja?
贾
Ja,
-你在干嘛  -兄弟 我饿死了
- What are you doing? - I'm starving, man.
你知道我有多久没见过水果了吗
You know how long it's been since I seen fruit?
你停下来吃东西
You're stopping to eat?
你嗑药了啊
Are you high?!
别骂我 你又不是我妈
Don't come at me, man. You're not my mama.
知道吗 你完了
You know what? You're done.
-你出局了  -什么
- You're gone. - What?
-等下  -我说了 走 你是个累赘
- Wait. - I said, walk! You're a liability!
等等等等 你说了你要带我出去
Wait. Wait. You said you'd get me out,
带我回家 我们说好了的
all the way home. That was the deal.
拉马尔 要是这个人再跟着我们
Ramal, this man follows us,
跟你的人说 开枪打死他
tell your men to shoot him.
很乐意
Gladly.
你去哪了 迈克尔
Where'd you go, Michael?
你在哪里
Where'd you go?
你们来了 兄弟们
There you are, my men.
抓住这些走狗 我们就能把他们干掉了
Seize these dogs so that we can put them down.
拉马尔
Ramal.
拉马尔 你在做什么
Ramal, what are you doing?
你以为你骗到我了吗
You thought you tricked me?
我们绕远路
Take the long way around while your friend...
好让你朋友先到这里拿到武器
gets here first to get weapons.
你想玩我 这是美国俚语吧
You were going to screw me. That's the American slang.
-不是吗  -是你想玩我
- Isn't it? - You were gonna screw me.
无话可说
So much for our word.
对敌人撒谎
Lying to enemies.
伊斯兰教称之为拓奇雅
It's called Taqiyya.
相机拿出来
Take off the camera.
我要让世界知道
I will show the world
对阿布·拉马尔不敬
what happens
会是什么下场
when you screw Abu Ramal.
跪下
On your knees!
-不可能  -让他们跪下
- It's not gonna happen. - Make them on their knees!
住手
Enough!
放下你们的武器
Drop your weapons.
离我弟弟远点儿
Step away from my brother.
林肯
Linc.
你有多爱你的弟弟
How much do you love this brother of yours?
你为什么不从车上下来
Why don't you step down from that truck?
停 停 停 事情不太对
Stop. Stop, stop, stop. No, it's not going down
听我说 好吗
like this, okay? Just...
你们等一下 我实在有太多问题要问我朋友了
stop. I got way too many questions for my friend here.
-退后  -我入狱
-Step back! -I went to prison for killing
是因为在酒吧打架失手打死一个人
a guy in a bar fight. I didn't even want
我本来根本不想卷入事端 他开始对我女朋友言语不干净
to get into it, okay? He starts talking yang to my girl.
我叫他走开
I tell him to beat it.
他拿出一把刀 我突然大怒
He pulls a knife, and I see red.
一秒之后
One second later,
我就拿着他滴血的刀 把他按在地上
I'm holding his bloody knife, and it's his body on the ground.
-你没有这么快  -一秒
- You're not that fast. - One second.
别这么做
Please don't do this.
你打不过的
You will lose.
听你朋友的话
Listen to your friend.
我是在跟你说 拉马尔
I'm talking to you, Ramal.
我说了 从车上下来
I told you! Step down from that truck.
把你们的武器拣起来
Pick up your weapons!
在你意识到之前 只有一秒钟反应时间
You've got one second till that one second happens.
去死吧
Go to hell.
来了更多人了
We got more coming!
-这边还有  -糟糕了
- And more over here! - This is a big problem.
我们快离开这鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
-你想见我们  -哎哟
- You wanted to see us? - Ouch.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
看看这反派
Behold the villain.
他到底是谁
Who the hell is this guy?
我哥哥
He's my brother.
我不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我不敢相信 简直不可思议
I just can't believe this. I can't believe this.
你怎么又进监狱了
Back at the prison. Why?
-你为什么那样说  -我必须否认
- Why did you say? - I had to deny you.
你在...你在拍我
You were... you were filming me.
-不能让他们知道  不能让谁知道
-They can't know.  -Who can't know?
-不能让他们知道我要越狱  -谁
- They can't know I'm getting out. - Who?
迟点再解释 先...
I'll explain everything later, just...
萨拉和..和迈克
Sara and-and Mike?
他们都好
They're good.
-他们没事  -谢天谢地
- They're fine. - Oh, thank God.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
一堆问不完的话 是吗
Questions just keep piling up, huh?
你在电视里
That's you.
我们都在
It's all of us.
他们在说什么
What are they saying?
伊斯兰国掌控了政府驻地
That ISIL has taken over the government station.
他们敬爱的首领 阿布·拉马尔
That their beloved leader, Abu Ramal,
已被杀害
has been martyred.
我们是罪魁祸首
That we're the ones that did it.
整个伊斯兰国军队都向我们宣战了
The entire army of ISIL just declared war on us.
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）